孩子们 吃早餐了 卢克 吃点水果吧
Kids, breakfast! Luke, why don't you have some fruit?
不用了 谢谢
Nah, I'm good.
行行行 我吃行了吧
Fine. I'll have some.
菲尔 开慢一点
Phil! Slow down!
不好意思 克莱尔
I'm sorry, Claire.
跟在家里不同 这里我是船长我说了算
Unlike at home, I'm the captain here.
我靠 菲尔 别闹了
Damn it, Phil, knock it off!
收到
Copy that.
我挺喜欢这个的
You know, I like having these.
咱们应该买几台放家里用
We should get some for the house.
不行 你别想每天用讲对机
No, you're not going to ask me "What time is lunch?"
问我"几点吃午饭"
every day through a talkie-walkie.
小卡 我们得谈谈这个
Cam, we need to talk about this.
我们家也有这种灯
We -- We have these lamps at home.
我们竟然用的船灯
Okay, we have boat lamps.
对啊 感觉好受人肯定
I know. It's so validating.
就像那次我们在狗粮广告里
It's like that time we saw our can opener
看到咱家的开罐器一样
in that dog-food commercial.
我们租了一辆船屋
We rented a houseboat.
我爸让我们来游湖
My dad wanted us to take a big lake trip
好能观赏到99年来首次的日全食
so we could see the first total eclipse in 99 years.
从小在农场长大
You know, growing up on a farm,
我一直幻想在湖上生活
I always fantasized about lake life.
对啊 谁都可以到湖里玩
Yeah. You know, anyone can go to the lake.
只有精英名流才能在湖面上睡觉
Only the elite can sleep on it.
以前小的时候 每年夏天
My parents used to take Claire and me
爸妈都会带我和克莱尔到湖上玩
every summer when we were kids.
我做梦都没想到我会嫁入一个湖上家族
Oh, I just never dreamed I would marry into a lake family.
我们家也用这个枕头
We have this pillow, too.
我开始质疑我们的品味了
I'm beginning to question our taste.
别傻了 我们品味可好了
Oh, don't be ridiculous. We have great taste.
你这是什么鬼
What's all this, then?
医生说了 我服用抗生素期间
The doctor said absolutely no sun
绝对不能晒太阳
while I'm on these antibiotics.
晒到会怎样
And what would happen?
因为如果不会危及生命
Because if it's anything short of death,
我觉得你都应该赌一把
I-I think you should risk it.
-早上好 -早安 有人饿了吗
- Morning. - Good Morning! Who's hungry?
曼尼 你的鸡蛋要什么吃法
Manny, how do you take your eggs?
吃上帝创造出来的原味
Like God made 'em.
曼尼 你在干嘛
Manny, what are you doing?
这不是曼尼
This isn't Manny.
是曼尼尔
It's Manuel.
他在试图为上大学打造新人设
He's trying to reinvent himself for college.
他想变成强壮安静的类型
He's going for a strong, silent type.
别试图定义我
Hey, don't try to define me, man.
"曼尼尔"只能撑个五分钟
"Manuel"'s gonna last five minutes.
人就是这样 我也没办法
It is what it is, man.
好了 大家听好了
All right, everybody, listen up.
-日蚀发生的确切时间是... -我们知道
- The eclipse is happening at exactly -- - We know, we know, we know.
-我们知道发生的确切时间 爸爸 -对
- We know exactly when it's happening, Dad. - Yeah.
你说过了
You told us.
那到时一定要回来这里
Then just make sure you get back here
-我们才能一起观看 -没问题
- so we can watch it together. - No problem.
爸爸 你认识"只是衣柜"的休·邓肯吗
Hey, Dad, you know Hugh Duncan from Just Closets?
那个管衣柜叫"衣橱"的
That pretentious half-Brit
做作的半英国佬吗
that refers to closets as "wardrobes"?
他去世了
He died.
我勒个去 我一直挺喜欢他的
Son of a gun. I always liked him.
发生这种事
Yeah, something like that happens
会让你意识到生命有多宝贵
makes you realize how precious life is, huh?
早上好 各位家人
Morning, fam!
谁快来杀了我吧
Somebody kill me.
本和我已经在一起几个月了
Ben and I have been dating a few months now,
一切进展得很顺利
and things have been going so well,
于是我决定邀请他参加我们的家庭旅行
I decided to invite him on our family vacation.
我们知道需要...
We knew it would take some --
听你说话再久我都不会腻
I could listen to you talk forever.
我们知道说服他们需要费一番功夫
We knew it would take some convincing.
我每天都要在办公室看到本那张蠢脸
It's bad enough that I have to see Ben's stupid face
已经很糟心了
at the office every day.
你竟然还想带他参加我们的旅行
You want to bring him on our trip?
就因为他让你心烦
Just because he bugs you
不代表这就会毁了你的假期
doesn't mean this will ruin your vacation.
他就是我需要度假的罪魁祸首之一
He's a huge reason why I need a vacation!
我觉得你们说的都有道理
I mean, I can see both sides.
有谁知道这些煎饼是不是无麸质的
Ohhh. Does anyone know if these pancakes are gluten-free?
-我受不了了 -什么 怎么了
- I can't! - Why? What's wrong?
我受不了再听你聊麸质
I can't listen to you talk about gluten anymore!
或者牙齿保持器和气传过敏原
Or mouth guards or airborne allergens
或任何你其他的怪毛病了
or any of your other weird afflictions!
-有谁看到我的大帽子了吗 -没有
- Has anyone seen my big hat? - No.
其实呢 一起旅行就是个大错误
You know what? Traveling together was a big mistake.
我们就 各玩各的吧
Let's just... do our own thing.
好吧
A-all right.
你们今天有什么安排
What are you guys up to today?
-划水 -船上的事
- Water skiing. - Boat stuff.
不是吧
Ay, no.
这是什么东西
What am I looking at?
放轻松 你们都表现得像是没见过长袍一样
Okay, relax. You all act like you've never seen a caftan before.
我今天需要能透气的全包式服装
I just needed full breathable coverage today.
还能看起来这么好看 简直赚到
The fact that it looks so great is just a bonus.
-这是什么 -卡通《泡泡孔雀鱼》
- What's that? - "Groovy Guppies."
我要连看上一季
I'm gonna binge-watch the last season.
我都没听过这节目
I never heard of it.
翘掉你妈要带你去做的活动
Get out of whatever your mommy's got you doing.
你的人生即将改变
Your life is about to change.
我要下船到那家小商店买墨镜
I'm going down to the little store to buy some sunglasses.
我想买好玩的款式
I'm thinking something fun.
好吧 别买太花哨艳俗的
All right. Well, don't get anything too garish.
尤物 岛上有派对
Hey, sexy! Party on the island!
来玩吧
Come by!
-赞 -正点
- Yum! - Yum!
-你在干什么 -刚才那是什么
- What are you doing? - What was that?
-那是个男生 -那是个女生
- That was a boy! - That was a girl!
-你在说什么 -你在说什么
- What are you talking about?! - What are you talking about?!
不管刚才那是什么
Whatever that was,
我们都要在本找到我之前去他或她的派对
we're going to his/her party before Ben finds me.
邓菲队 五人组 你们准备好出发了吗
Team Dunphy, D to the five. You guys ready to go?
你们想做什么
Yeah, what do you feel like doing?
我们刚才在想也许可以去远足
We were thinking maybe a hike?
看看植物 动物 还有...
A little flora, fauna, and --
别了吧 我们要去参加派对
Forget it. We're going to a party.
但你们如果想找些好玩活动
But if you're looking for something fun,
租赁处那人给了我们个宣传册
the rental guy gave us this pamphlet.
谢了 我们已经有一个了 不过...
Thanks. We already got one, but --
你们的和我们的不一样
Oh. Yours is different.
帆伞 水上滑板
Parasailing, wakeboarding...
水上喷气背包
jetpacking?
我们的写着日出椅上瑜伽
Ours has sunrise chair yoga,
湖岸上画水彩
watercolors at water's edge,
还有个叫观云的活动
and something called... cloud study?
他们给外公的也是那个版本
Yeah, they gave that one to Grandpa, too.
他给我们的是老年人的版本吗
We got the old people one?
不 他们为什么那么做
No! Why would they do that?
貌似您二老今天有很多蓬松的云朵可看
Looks like you guys got some fluffy ones out today.
那朵云看起来像只小兔子
That one looks like a bunny.
真的
Oh, yeah.
感觉我们就身在法国圣特罗佩一样
Ah. It feels like we're in St. Tropez.
我不喜欢湖
I don't trust lakes.
在我老家 这种湖专门用来抛毒弃尸
Where I come from, this is where we dump drugs and dead bodies.
你猜怎么着
You know what?
让我带你来一趟小舟观光
I am gonna give you a little boat tour
向你展示这片湖所有的美好之处
and show you this lake in all of its glory,
但你得抱着开放的心态
but you need to keep an open mind.
好吧
Okay, fine.
让我们环游这片液体墓地吧
Let's ride around the liquid graveyard.
妈妈 乘小船让我肚肚疼
Mama, riding on small boats makes my tummy hurt.
我能和莉莉留在这吗
Can I stay with Lily?
好的 宝贝
Si, papi.
那是斯科蒂 一个在这湖边长大的孩子
It was Scotty -- this local lake kid
我13岁度假时与他结识
I met on vacation when I was 13.
我当时疯狂迷上他了 所以在假期最后一天
I had a huge crush on him, so on the last day,
我决定冒险一搏 吻了他
I decided to take a chance and I kissed him.
那是我第一次亲吻男生
It was my first time ever kissing a boy,
所以当他向后躲开
so when he pulled away
并告诉我他"不感兴趣"时
and said that he wasn't "into this,"
我特别羞愧
I was humiliated.
显然我误读了一些信号 他是直男
I mean, I'd obviously misread signals. He was straight.
那之后的五年我都没对任何男生发过攻势
It was five years before I ever made a move on a guy again.
即便五年后 我也不敢
And even then, I wouldn't dare
除非对方弯到有如花蝴蝶一般
unless he was basically floating across the room.
这就是为什么我现在的老公是...
Which is why I ended up with --
你懂的
Well, you know.
找到你要的东西了吗 兄弟
Finding everything okay, buddy?
是的
Yeah.
第一次来 有点...
Just, uh, first time here, so, uh...
你看起来挺面熟的 我认识你吗
You look familiar. Do I know you?
不 不不不
No! Nah, nah, nah.
我只是来买点湖边必备品
Just picking up a few, uh, lake essentials.
好了
Okay.
你要抢我钱吗
Are you robbing me?
天啊 不
God, no. No, um...
这样吧 都拿去吧
You know what? Good.
我读了一些脸书上写给休·邓肯的悼词
I started reading the tributes to Hugh Duncan on Facebook.
写悼词的人特别多
There were a ton of them.
人们不停地说他生前是个多好的人
People going on and on about what a great guy he was.
"休爷爷有次给了我一个老式听诊器
"Grandpa Hugh once gave me a vintage stethoscope,
那激励我成为了一名儿科肿瘤学家"
which inspired me to become a pediatric oncologist."
这让我很好奇我死后别人会怎么说我
Made me wonder what people will say about me when I'm gone.
亲爱的 我想把我的天文望远镜给你
Honey, I want you to have my telescope.
希望它能激励你爱上科学
May it inspire you to love science.
我已经爱科学了
I already love science.
我觉得这是你重大的人生转折点
This feels like a real turning point.
你有天会想把这段佳话告诉别人
You know, it's a story you'll want to tell people.
"他总教导我要有摘星之志"
"He always told me to reach for the stars."
谢谢您
Thanks?
艾丽克斯 你在哪
Alex! Where are you?
是本 告诉他你今天都没见过我
Ohh! It's Ben. Tell him you haven't seen me.
我不想和他说话
I don't want to talk to him.
艾丽克斯
Alex?
我们不过出去几个小时
We'll only be gone for a couple hours.
乔和莉莉不会有事的
Joe and Lily will be fine.
等等 你瞧
Oh, wait. Look.
是那个人很好的湖上管家
There's that nice lake butler
他之前帮我拿过行李
that helped me earlier with my bags.
先生 先生
Senor. Senor.
你能帮我们看几个小时孩子吗
Could you take care of our kids for a couple of hours?
无论你在湖上能挣多少我都付你双倍
I will pay you double what you make working for the lake.
不是吧
Seriously?
我们认识的
You know me.
我们一起乘车去的机场
We rode to the airport together.
你能不能帮我们看孩子吧
Can you watch our kids or not?
其实我现在有点...
Actually, I'm kind of, uh --
艾丽克斯
Alex?
他们对什么食物过敏吗
Any food allergies I should know about?
这挺有趣的 就咱俩
This is fun -- just the two of us.
是啊 这些手杖真是登山神器啊
Yeah. And the walking sticks are a real game changer.
等一下 我们到观景点了
Hold the phone. We've hit a vista.
看来你不是这里唯一的小山雀
Looks like you're not the only mountain chickadee around here.
你发现了一只吗
You spotted one?
等轮到你时 注意它颈部的黑色羽毛
When it's your turn, note her black bib.
好的
Okay.
-我的天啊 -它是不是好优雅
- Oh, my God. - Isn't she majestic?
菲尔 我们就是他们
Phil, we're them.
我们和老年人宣传册的封面一样一样
We're the cover of the old people's pamphlet.
这是要"闹哪样"
Well, that's a fine "How do ya do."
连册子上这人都不会说这么过时的话
Oh, even this guy wouldn't say that!
你说得对
You're right!
我们这是怎么了
What is wrong with us?
你看
Look!
那才是我们该做的
That's what we should be doing!
我们只要想办法保持年轻和冒险精神就好
We just need to find ways to stay young and adventurous.
我支持你 亲爱的
I'm with you, honey.
-我们走 -太好了
- Let's go! - Yes! Yes!
我不再需要你们了
I don't need you anymore!
天啊 这东西习惯后还挺难戒的
Boy, you really get used to those things.
我也不想对本这么狠心
It's not that I want to be mean to Ben.
只是他有时真的很烦人
He can just be so annoying sometimes.
我知道人无完人
And I know nobody's perfect,
但难道那意味着我必须无视他所有缺点吗
but does that mean I have to ignore all of his flaws?
还是说我才是问题所在
Or is the issue me?
难道我理想中的人根本不存在吗
A-Am I just looking for something that doesn't exist?
我真的能做到无条件去爱一个人吗
Am I even capable of loving someone unconditionally?
我们明白 你有男朋友
We get it. You have a boyfriend.
那是那个男生的摩托艇
Hey, there's that guy's jet ski.
那个女生的摩托艇
That girl's jet ski.
不管是男是女 对我有兴趣 老娘就要了
Whatever it was, it was into me, and I'm kissing it.
帮我保管好别沾水 美人儿
Keep this dry for me, Pretty.
我们走遍了整座岛
We walked around that whole island.
一个俊男靓女都没有
No hot boys, girls -- nothing.
只有一大堆鸟
Just a bunch of birds.
甚至都不是好看的鸟
And not even hot birds.
我们的船呢
Hey, where's our boat?
不见了
It's gone.
他们的水上摩托也不见了
And so are their jet skis.
他们把我们引到这来仙人跳
They lured us out here and stole our stuff.
白痴 你还以为那女生是真的喜欢你
You idiot. You thought that girl really liked you.
"休是世上最好的岳父
"Hugh was the world's greatest father-in-law.
他总是在一旁支持我 随时为我伸出援手
He was always there for me, ready to lend a helping hand."
你在干什么 菲尔
What are you doing, Phil?
我在等克莱尔
Oh, I'm just waiting out here
等她换好衣服我们就去悬崖跳水
while Claire changes for our cliff dive.
感觉你需要人帮忙涂这麻烦的防晒霜
Looks like you could use some help with that pesky sunscreen.
-这么好 -对啊
- Really? - Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks!
来
There you go.
好痒
It tickles!
-菲尔 -我懂 我懂
- Listen, Phil -- I know, I know.
-把这件事忘掉 -是必需得记得
- This never happened. - Oh, it happened.
永远不要忘记你岳父这双强健的大手
Never forget how these strong father-in-law hands
给你带来的愉悦
gave you pleasure.
"我的爸爸休曾给予我箴言
"My dad, Hugh, once gave me the best advice --
要怀抱勇气去选择自己的路
have the courage to choose your own path,
而不是别人希望你走的路
not the path others expect of you.
这些话改变了我的一生"
Those words changed my life forever."
发生什么事了 儿子
What's going on, son?
我知道肯定发生了什么事 我真心在乎你
I know there's a story there, and I really care.
没事
It's nothing.
放下心防
Walls down, please.
好吧 我告诉你
Ugh. Okay, fine.
这事挺难堪的
Um, it's really embarrassing.
我在渔具用品店碰到了一个员工
Uh, I ran into this guy who works at the bait shop.
那是家同志酒吧吗
Is that a gay bar?
不是 是真的渔具用品店
No, an actual bait shop.
多年前我对他发动过攻势
And I came on to him years ago.
结果发现他是直男
It turns out he was straight.
我受到的创伤至今还没愈合
And I'm -- I'm still traumatized by it.
让我给你点建议
Let me give you some advice.
朝难堪跑去 而非逃离它
Run toward embarrassment, not away from it.
明白了吗
You got that?
等等 什么意思
Wait. What?
去跟他谈谈
Go talk to the guy.
朝难堪跑去 而非逃离它
Run toward embarrassment, not away from it,
如此才能击倒它
and you take away its power.
这个建议还真不坏
That's actually not the worst advice.
简直棒极了
It's great advice.
你应该把它记下来
In fact, you should write it down.
感觉哪天可以再引用
It feels quotable.
知道吗
You know what?
我要重新站起来面对他
I am. I'm going back there.
你能做到的 米奇尔
You got this, Mitchell.
记住这是你爸爸又一次
Just think of it as one more time
帮助你解决了你这些基佬问题
when your dad helped you out with all this gay business.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
歌洛莉亚 你见过这么纯净透蓝的湖水吗
Oh, Gloria, have you ever seen such pristine blue water?
那个是浮尸袋吗
Is that a floating duffel bag?
不是 是个浮标
No, that's just a buoy.
一个男孩吗[音似]
A boy?!
不是 是浮标
No, a buoy. A --
我的防晒衫卡在...
Oh, my caftan's stuck in the --
太阳
The sun!
快好了
Almost done.
再吹几下就好了 好吗
Just a few more puffs, okay?
不能看卡通《泡泡孔雀鱼》就好吗
Can't we just watch "Groovy Guppies"?
相信我 这个好玩多了
Trust me, this will be way more fun.
别担心 他不会有事
Don't worry. He'll be fine.
磨快点
Go faster!
你不是在拉小提琴 你是要生火
It's not a violin. You're trying to start a fire.
放轻松啊 兄弟
Hey, chill, man!
这样没用的
That's never gonna work.
我们得找个更好的办法通知别人我们在这
We need a better way to let someone know we're out here.
谁带镜子了吗
Anyone have a mirror?
好主意 我们可以反射阳光提醒过往的飞机
Good idea. We can reflect the sun onto a passing plane.
不 我只是想照照镜子
No, I just have a feeling that my hair
看看我完美的秀发
looks really good right now.
我的小指头扎到木刺了
I got a splinter in my pinkie!
看来硬汉的曼尼尔已死
I think we have a time of death on Manuel.
闭嘴 都怪你
Shut up! It's your fault
要我快速钻木取火
for making me rub those sticks together so fast.
怪我 要不是这两个蜥蜴脑袋
My fault? We wouldn't even be out here
管不住裤腰带
if it weren't for these two lizard brains
我们根本就不会来这儿
not being able to keep it in their pants.
你只是在嫉妒我们不会因为有人爱
You're just jealous because we don't hate ourselves
而自怨自艾
for being attracted to other people.
拜托 我才不要听一个今早发短信
Please! I'm not accepting a psych evaluation
让我把他从厕所救出去的人
from somebody who texted me for help
来给我做的什么心理评估
getting out of the bathroom this morning.
船上的锁不一样嘛
Boat locks are different!
其实他说得对
He's right, you know.
这是你第一次带男友出来旅行
This is your first time bringing a boy on vacation,
他跟我们全家坐在一起的一瞬间
and the second he sat down with the whole family,
恋情一下变得太有真实感
things started to get a little too real for you.
所以你就开始对本吹毛求疵
So you started to pick Ben apart
好为自己把他推开找借口
so you could justify pushing him away.
我没有吧
I don't think I do that.
我这么做了吗
Do I do that?
我真的这么做了
I do do that.
其实仔细想想 我跟你也差不多
When you think about it, I'm in a similar situation.
上大学的事越来越有真实感了
College is getting a little real,
我有点担心又多一群新的人排挤我
and maybe I'm nervous about a whole new group of people
所以我把曼尼的一面藏了起来
rejecting me, so I hid Manny away.
说到底
After all...
没见过 就伤不到
can't hurt a man they'll never meet.
-我想念曼尼尔了 -是啊
- Ugh. I miss Manuel. - Yeah.
-你好 -又来抢劫我了吗
- Oh, hi. - Uh-oh. Here to rob me again?
刚才很抱歉 我不是有意要吓你
Sorry about that. I-I didn't mean to scare you.
没有 你根本没吓着我
Oh, no. You didn't scare me at all.
事实上我才是那个抢钱的
As a matter of fact, I'm the one robbing you.
在镇上这些虫子才卖五分钱
Back in town, these worms are 5 cents each.
听着
Ah. So, um, listen.
其实我们 我们以前就认识了
We -- We actually do know each other.
我是米奇尔·普里契特 89年暑假 记得吗
Uh, Mitchell Pritchett. Summer of '89?
我送了你我的任天堂游戏机
I let you have my Nintendo Game Boy?
米奇·普里契 当然了
Mitchy Pritchy! Of course!
当时可生那游戏机的气了
You were mad about that Game Boy
因为你爸给你买的是游戏机
'cause your dad got you that
而不是什么雪儿的专辑
instead of, like, some Cher album.
《如果时间倒转》专辑
"If I Could Turn Back Time."
我来这里就是因为这些
Which brings me to why I'm here.
我不确定你是否还记得
Um, I don't know if you remember this,
但我有一次想亲你 我...
but I tried to kiss you once, and I've --
我只是经常... 我对此深感愧疚
I've just always -- I've felt really terrible about it.
我只想说声抱歉
And I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
对 没事 我都忘得差不多了
Oh, yeah. No, I barely remember that.
我们过了个很愉快的暑假 别放心上了
We had a great summer. Don't think twice about it.
这真是... 让人松了口气
Oh! That is -- that is such a relief.
还记得我们偷了我爸的卡车 然后开去赌场吗
Remember we stole my dad's truck and took it to the casino?
-记得啊 -我想逗你开心
- Right. - I was trying to cheer you up
因为那个恶霸老是把你推到湖里去
because that bully kept pushing you in the lake.
那是克莱尔 对 不过我们现在挺好的
Claire. Yeah. No, we're cool now.
听我说 很高兴见到你
Um, so, listen, good to see you.
很高兴见到你
Great to see you.
听我说 谢谢你理解我
Oh, and, hey, listen. Thank you so much for understanding.
很多直男根本不可能这么友好
A lot of straight guys wouldn't have been so nice.
直男 我不是直男
Straight? I'm not straight.
抱歉 你说什么
I'm sorry. What?
我比三只塞在水桶里的龙虾还要"弯"曲
I'm gayer than three crawdaddies in a bucket.
你们要买鱼饵吗
Were you guys looking for bait?
我刚进了一些加州短虫
I just got in some California Short Worms
绝对不是把正常虫子切成两半的啊
that are definitely not regular worms cut in half.
你准备好了吗
You ready to do this?
那当然
So ready!
跳进这个悬崖水底就表示
Jumping off this cliff represents
我们像冒险者一样跳进我们的未来
jumping into our future as adventurers.
好了 数到三
Okay. Count of three.
一 二 三
One, two, three!
菲尔
Phiiiilllll!
亲爱的
Honey...
-怎么了 -我很抱歉
- What happened? - I'm so sorry.
我最后一秒退缩了
I bailed at the last second.
但我现在准备好了 我发誓
But I'm ready now. I promise.
-准备好了 -一二三
- Ready? - One, two, three!
我靠...
Come o--
你在这儿呢
Oh. Hey. There you are.
我觉得你好像
Um, I feel like you
数到二就抢跳了
jumped on "two." Oh!
亲爱的 跳 很好玩 真的超好玩
Honey, jumping -- it's fun. It's really fun.
但是重点是跟你一起跳
But the point was to do it with you.
所以如果不行的话...
So if that's gonna be a problem --
不 我...我真的想尝试一下
No, I-I definitely want to do it.
但问题是
It's just that I'm having
我控制不住我的腿
a hard time getting my legs to cooperate.
好吧 你得推我
Okay. You're gonna have to push me.
-你确定吗 -确定
- Are you sure? - Yes.
用力推我一下 我没事
Just one hard push, and I'm good.
好的
Okay.
来
Here...
走
we...
你
go --
我去...
Oh, come o--
别再这么晃这玩意儿了
Stop rocking this thing so much.
我要开始晕船了
I am getting seasick.
你可真可怜 要是你...
Well, you poor thing. Maybe if you had --
抽筋 抽筋 抽筋 抽筋了
Uh-oh! Cramp, cramp, cramp, cramp, cramp, cramp!
我小腿抽筋了 小腿抽筋了
Calf's cramping up! Calf's cramping up!
歌洛莉亚 快帮我揉我小腿
Gloria, I need you to rub my calf!
不 我不要碰这水
No! I'm not gonna touch that water!
歌洛莉亚 我现在疼死了
Gloria, I'm in so much pain!
你得稍微用力帮我压一下
You got to put a little pressure on it!
用力压一下我的小腿
Put a little pressure on my calf!
好了
Okay, fine!
我够不着
I can't get it.
我掉进湖里了
I'm in the lake!
不要啊
Ay, no! Ay! Ay!
你知道吗 我小腿不抽了
Oh! What do you know? My cramp's gone.
我又来了 问个小问题
Hi, again. Quick question.
鱼饵恕不退换
No refunds on the bait.
你买的时候肯定是活的
They were alive when you bought them.
是米奇啊 抱歉
Oh. Hey, Mitchy. Sorry.
我就是好奇 在我们一起玩过后多久
Just curious -- um, how long after we hung out
你意识到你是同性恋的
did you realize that you were gay?
不... 其实是在那之前好几年
Oh, no, it was -- it was years before that.
好吧 所以那时候
Oh. Okay. So -- So, back then,
你说你... "不感兴趣"时
when you said that you -- you weren't "into this,"
是指对我不感兴趣吗
you meant that you weren't into me.
-这个嘛... -因为我肯定是当时方圆几里内
- Well... - Because I must have been the only gay kid
-唯一同性恋小孩 对吧 -我不...
- around for miles, right? - Oh, I don't --
是啦 基本上是这样没错
Yeah, I mean, technically, yeah.
让我理一下
Let me get this right.
你待在这么个破地儿 根本没别人可选
You're in the middle of nowhere, with no other options,
在一个刮点风都"性奋"的年纪
at an age where a boy gets excited by the wind,
然后你看着我 表示"还是算了吧"
and you looked at me, and you said, "Ooh, pass."
我...
W-- I --
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I feel bad.
虽然已经是30年前的事了
It was 30 years ago, though.
你想要点...免费鱼饵吗
You want some... free bait?
要买诱饵吗
Have a lure?
貌似我的确没有"诱惑力"
Apparently, I don't have allure.
好了 歌洛莉亚 那里有家店
Okay, Gloria, there's a store.
过去 随便买个能盖住我的东西
Go in there. Get me something to cover me up with -- anything.
但如果有颜色可选 不要黄色和绿色
But if there is a color choice, avoid yellow and green.
会显得我气色不好
It washes me out.
是啊 小卡 我也很想帮你
Oh, yeah, Cam, I would love to help you --
就像你帮我掉进那个肮脏的湖里一样
the same way you helped me fall into that filthy lake!
孩子们 小心裸男啊
Hey, kids! Watch out for the naked man!
-什么 歌洛莉亚 -祝你好运
- What? Gloria? - Good luck.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
克莱尔
Claire!
Claire!!
快看
Look!
我搞了个喷射背包
I got a jetpack!
我不想成为拖累你的人
I don't want to be the one to hold you back!
我没想到会这么难控...
I didn't think it'd be this hard to contr--
菲尔
Phil!
天啊
Oh, my God!
你看 我们才不无聊呢
Look! We're not boring!
我们还很有冒险精神呢
We're still adventurous!
我看出来了
I can see that!
我真是太为你骄傲了
I'm so proud of you!
我好爱你
I love you so much.
克莱尔
Claire?
没事的 宝贝 别怕
Oh, no, honey. Don't worry.
只是日食而已
I-It's just the eclipse.
我分不清那边是天那边是地了
I can't tell if I'm headed up or down!
你好 黑暗 我的老朋友[歌词]
Hello darkness, my old friend
大家人呢
Where is everybody?
算了 不来也无所谓
Ah, who needs them?
这是个挺特别的时刻对吧 乔
This is a pretty special moment, huh, Joey?
估计你也不会记得这段时光
Eh, you're never gonna remember any of this.
如果可以的话
If you don't mind,
我是想出去看日食的
I -- I do want to go outside and see the eclipse.
我还没完呢 你给我听好了
Oh, I'm not done. Just -- Just so you know,
很多人觉得我特有魅力好吗
plenty of people find me very attractive, okay,
包括我超赞 而且完全不懒散的老公
including my amazing husband, who is no slouch himself.
请问您有卖穆穆袍吗
Hi. Do you sell muumuus?
我现在要去找我老公了
And I am gonna go find him right now.
-那是什么 -天啊 是本
- Hey, what's that? - Oh, my God! It's Ben!
他来救我了
He came to rescue me!
我独自飘在水上
I was out there all alone.
突然就黑了
And then it got really dark.
而且我快渴死了
And I'm so thirsty.
靠 我沾到了泥
Ew! I got mud on me.
对不起 我不该对你撒气
I'm so sorry I lashed out at you.
我好像每次跟人太走心就会这样
I think I do it when I start getting close to someone.
但我想跟你走心
But I want to be close to you.
我也想啊
I want that, too.
来吧 我们可以拿这个当桨
Come on. We can use this as an oar.
一船载不下所有人啊
Oh, there's not enough room for all of us.
我们俩可以在这里等你们...
Well, the two of us can stay while you --
我再回来救你
I'll come back for you!
好吧
All right.
哎哟哟 哪来的稀客啊
Well, well, well. Look who finally showed up.
或许我们99年后可以再试着看一次
Maybe we can try this again in another 99 years.
其实 下一次日全食只要再过
Actually, there'll be another total eclipse again
-7年就能看到 -没人想听你的傻逼科学
- in the next seven years. - No one wants your stupid science, Alex!
我就要求了一件事
I asked for one thing --
以我为中心 一起创造这一段回忆
to share a memory with all of us with me at the center of it!
还有
And by the way,
因为是日食大热期 船费还是超贵费率
I had to pay surge boat rates because of eclipse fever!
能进他的抱怨排行榜了
This is an all-time rant.
对啊 前三名吧 84年圣诞那次
Oh, yeah, top three. It goes Christmas '84,
还有他预定了猪肉
that wedding where he ordered the pork
结果送来了鸡肉的婚礼那次
but they gave him the chicken instead,
然后就是日食周末
and eclipse weekend.
我唯一去那次婚礼的原因
The only reason I went to that wedding
就是他妈的为了吃那个猪肉
was because of the damn pork!
你们以后就只会记得我这件事了吗
Is this gonna be the only thing you guys remember about me?!
你搞这出是因为休·邓肯去世后
Does this have something to do with Hugh Duncan dying
他脸书上的那些夸赞之词吗
and all those Facebook tributes?
-你放屁 -等等 你是想要故意制造美好回忆
- No!! - Wait, w-were you trying to manufacture nice moments
所以你去世以后我们会说你好话吗
so that we'll say good things about you when you're gone?
等等 所以你才送我你的天文望远镜吗
Wait. Is that why you gave me your telescope?
擦防晒霜呢 那都是虚情假意吗
And the -- the sunscreen? That wasn't real?
我懒得跟你们说了
I don't want to talk about this!
杰 你上哪去呢
Jay, where are you going?!
我的老天爷啊 老爸 别走啊
Oh, for God's sakes! Dad! Come back!
外公 别走啊
Grandpa, stop!
我们有大把属于你的美好回忆啊
We have tons of great memories of you!
你就是说了哄我而已
You're just saying that!
谁快举个例子
Someone think of an example!
你以前出差回来
You used to bring me back magnets
都会给我带各式各样的纪念磁铁
every time you went away on a business trip!
超级有心
It was so thoughtful!
当你发现我喜欢杏仁奶的时候
Yeah, when you found out I was into almond milk,
你去量贩超市给我买了一大桶保久杏仁奶
you went to Costco and got me that giant thing of almond milk!
你喜欢喝 而且不会变质
Well, you like it, and it doesn't go bad.
我妈妈去世时 你给我发了一周短信
When my mom died, you texted me every day
天天关心我好不好
for a week to check on me!
你吃小熊糖总是给我留红色小熊
You always save me the red gummy bears
因为那是我最喜欢的口味
because they're my favorite!
也给我留了绿色小熊
And me the green ones!
还给了我舒适生活与东西
Also, the nice life and stuff!
而且你 你超会保存
And -- And -- And you're really good
我跟米奇尔小时候的那些照片
at saving old pictures of me and Mitchell as kids!
例子开始打混了
Getting a little general.
"朝难堪跑去 而非逃离它
"Run toward embarrassment, not away from it,
如此才能击倒它"
and you take away its power"!
我会永远记得这句话
I'm always gonna remember that!
行吧
Good enough.
"朝难堪跑去"
"Run toward embarrassment"?
这话是什么鬼啊
What does that even mean?
我也不懂 但他需要这鼓励
I don't know. He needs this.
你为什么要推我下水
Why would you push me in like that?
干嘛啦 大家都笑了
Relax. Everybody laughed.
♪ 回首 ♪
♪ Turn around. ♪
♪ 有时候 ♪
♪ Every now and then ♪
♪ 我会感到有些孤单 ♪
♪ I get a little bit lonely ♪
♪ 但你从不来陪伴我 ♪
♪ and you're never coming round. ♪
♪ 回首 ♪
♪ Turn around. ♪
我 ♪ 有时候我也会厌烦 ♪
Me. ♪ Every now and then I get a little bit tired ♪
♪ 听到自己眼泪落下 ♪
♪ of listening to the sound of my tears. ♪
♪ 回首吧 ♪
♪ Turn around, ♪
♪ 明眸的你 ♪
♪ bright eyes. ♪
-轮到谁 -老爸
- Who? - Dad.
来嘛杰 大家都会记得这一刻
Come on Jay, everybody will remember it.
这是强买强卖
That's extortion.
拜托嘛
Come on.
♪ 有时我会崩溃 ♪
♪ Every now and then I fall apart ♪
-这就对啦 - ♪ 而今夜我需要你的陪伴 ♪
- There it is. - ♪ and I need you now tonight ♪
♪ 从没有如此需要你过 ♪
♪ and I need you more than ever. ♪
这玩意是歌吗
Is this even a song?
♪ 曾几何时 ♪
♪ Once upon a time, ♪
♪ 我坠入过爱河 ♪
♪ I was falling in love, ♪
♪ 但如今我坠入无间地狱 ♪
♪ but now I'm only falling apart. ♪
♪ 对此我束手无策 ♪
♪ There's nothing I can do ♪
♪ 这场心的全食♪
♪ with a total eclipse of the heart. ♪
对了 本呢
Hey. Where's Ben?